Guide to the Gulf Oil Corporation Reston records, 1963
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Gulf Oil Corporation Reston records
1963
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Gulf Oil Corporation
C0144
0.5 linear feet (1 box)
This collection of papers documents the investment of $4 million from the Gulf Oil Corporation for the purpose of developing Reston, Virginia.All of the records are dated September 11, 1963. The collection is small and all 14 folders are contained within a single document case.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the Gulf Oil Corporation on October 16, 1989.
Historical Information
The Gulf Oil Corporation was founded in 1901 when oil was discovered in Spindletop, Texas. The company invested millions of dollars into the development of gasoline in the early Twentieth Century. By the early 1930s, it had grown into a major United States corporation. The corporation continued to grow into the 1960s.
During that time Gulf Oil became an investor into Robert E. Simon's planned community in Reston, Virginia. As one of his principal investors, Gulf Oil stepped in to save the project from bankruptcy in 1967. The Gulf Reston officials continued development of the New Town and for more than ten years encouraged a diversity in housing sizes, styles, and prices.
Scope and Content
This collection of papers documents the investment of $4 million from the Gulf Oil Corporation for the purpose of developing Reston, Virginia. All of the records are dated September 11, 1963. The collection is small and all 14 folders are contained within a single document case.
There is only series in this collection, and it consists of exhibit files. The series has the loan proposal from the Gulf Oil Corporation and each exhibit that was presented. There are 12 exhibits in all with an exhibit index in the first folder of the collection.
Arrangement
Organized into one series.
Series 1: Exhibit Files, 1963 (Box 1)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
The Special Collections and Archives also holds the Planned Community Archives and other personal papers and organizational records that document Reston, Virginia, and other planned communities.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Gulf Oil Corporation.
Geographical Names:
Reston (Va.)
Subjects:
Housing--Virginia--Reston.; Planned communities--Virginia--Reston.
Contents List
- Series 1: Exhibit Files, 1963; (1 box)
  This is the only series in this collection with 14 folders included in the single document case. The series documents the proposal from the Gulf Oil Corporation and the 12 exhibits that were presented for the loan.
  - Exhibit Index, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    171.1
  - Proposed loan for Palindrome, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    171.2
  - Exhibit 1, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    171.3
  - Exhibit 2, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    171.4
  - Exhibit 3, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    171.5
  - Exhibit 4, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    171.6
  - Exhibit 5, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    171.7
  - Exhibit 6, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    171.8
  - Exhibit 7, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    171.9
  - Exhibit 8, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    171.10
  - Exhibit 9, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    171.11
  - Exhibit 10, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    171.12
  - Exhibit 11, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    171.13
  - Exhibit 12, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    171.14